<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Radical Passive</title>
    <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Radical Passive</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://radicalpassive.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Minsk Light Industry Accessory Factory. Facade renovation</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/light-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/light-industry/</guid>
      <description>Minsk Light Industry Accessory Factory. Facade renovation
The building of a former accessories factory is located in the central part of Minsk and dates back to the second half of the 20th century. It is a typical example of functionalism in soviet architecture.
The new owner wanted to transform the empty building into a business hub where IT-companies coexist with educational establishments and cultural institutions. We were asked to adapt the run-down facades for the new function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee shop in Minsk</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/coffee-shop-in-minsk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/coffee-shop-in-minsk/</guid>
      <description>Coffee shop in Minsk
There are coffee shops where you feel at home. Their design is not saturated with colour, wallpaper patterns, complex material combinations, heavy décor. They&amp;rsquo;re simple places, where it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have breakfast any day of the week. Their most important thing is the smell of coffee and freshly baked goods, an atmospheric playlist and lots of familiar faces. The space itself is just a backdrop.
The coffee house is located in an old flat in the Osmolovka district.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marx. Bookstore and coffee shop</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/marx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/marx/</guid>
      <description>Marx. Bookstore and coffee shop
The concept of the project is based on the idea of combining a bookstore, a coffee shop and a small art gallery in a single space. Divided into two parts by a massive wall, the space along Marx Street organically accommodates these functions. The integrity of the space is ensured by two wide portals in the wall and a uniform layout. We tried to avoid the usual &amp;lsquo;catering&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;shop&amp;rsquo; typologies and instead create an informal, friendly atmosphere with free-standing armchairs and small light tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knomary. Office</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/knomary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/knomary/</guid>
      <description>Knomary office
The starting point for our design was the initially complex configuration of the space, the wide range of wall materials, variations in ceiling height and floor level. To create a comfortable environment, we decided to tie the existing surfaces together with a common light grey colour, against which the black pavilion with private offices and a call booth stands out. This way we were free to introduce a variety of complementary materials and shapes of furniture: stainless steel, light wood, red textile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Touchable distance” Exhibition design</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/touchable-distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/touchable-distance/</guid>
      <description>“Touchable distance” Exhibition design
The unequivocal times we’re currently facing have entailed an abrupt change in the ways we interact with each other, and our perception of the surrounding world. This shift in our form of communication has not only led to societal frustration, but also pushed us to rethink familiar concepts. Daily life and human behavior have significantly changed with a sense of increased fear and anxiety. Breaking away from our physical connections, in the most basic sense, we are forced to seek interaction online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melancholy space</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/melancholy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/melancholy/</guid>
      <description>Melancholy space
Melancholy is a form of mental illness manifested in a prolonged state of sadness. Characteristic for melancholy is a solemn and pensive mood, often the result of a more thoughtful view on life. In small doses it is a defence reaction of the psyche, a restorative slumber bringing rebirth.
Postmodernism created an environment brimming with signs and meanings. This obscures the distinction between essential and secondary. An apartment leaves you alone with yourself, lets you escape the belarusian reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor and leisure club</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/labour-and-leisure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/labour-and-leisure/</guid>
      <description>Labor and leisure club
Located in Minsk and built around the 1950s, the building represents a typical example of soviet architecture. To include it in the modern economical and cultural contexts while preserving its architectural identity was the leading motive of the project.
The building is a legacy of the soviet industrial architecture of the mid 20th century. The combination of red walls with white window frames and decor was one of the characteristic features of industrial buildings of that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yard. A music venue</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/yard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/yard/</guid>
      <description>Yard. A music venue
Concept for the development of the former Experimental Plant of Technological Equipment in Minsk
The development of decayed industrial sites is a key factor in the renewal of Minsk. Tucked away amid residential quarters, such territories are often more viable than specially designed public spaces. Despite its enclosed nature and isolation from the streets, the Experimental Plant of Technological Equipment too has the potential to become a full-fledged and successful place.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
