<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Radical Passive</title>
    <link>https://radicalpassive.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Radical Passive</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://radicalpassive.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Office</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/office/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/office/</guid>
      <description>Radical Passive is an architectural group formed in 2019 with offices in Minsk and Brussels. We create new architecture of public spaces, buildings, interiors and furniture elements, we develop projects of renovation and reconstruction. Our works are free to speak their own language, without excess meaning but radically aimed at evoking feelings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camille</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/camille/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/camille/</guid>
      <description>Camille
A big enveloping cloud. It&amp;rsquo;s bigger than a normal chair: its dimensions defy common standards. You don&amp;rsquo;t sit on this chair, you stay in it. Furthermore, sitting in the chair is just one of the possible poses. Its soft, rounded shape gives it a relaxed and stable character. The upholstery is made of white textured corduroy.
The chair is inspired by the works of the French studio Pierre Augustin Rose and the Russian designer Olga Engel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marx. Bookstore and coffee shop</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/marx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/marx/</guid>
      <description>Marx. Bookstore and coffee shop
The concept of the project is based on the idea of combining a bookstore, a coffee shop and a small art gallery in a single space. Divided into two parts by a massive wall, the space along Marx Street organically accommodates these functions. The integrity of the space is ensured by two wide portals in the wall and a uniform layout. We tried to avoid the usual &amp;lsquo;catering&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;shop&amp;rsquo; typologies and instead create an informal, friendly atmosphere with free-standing armchairs and small light tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auguste</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/auguste/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/auguste/</guid>
      <description>Auguste
The chair is on the border between a functional object and a sculpture. It was specifically designed to stand out in the interior. It has no backrest, making it more of a cushioned stool. The armrests flow smoothly from the shape of the seat. The solid base gives the entire structure stability. The distinctive shape is accentuated by the black velour upholstery.
The chair is inspired by the works of the French studio Pierre Augustin Rose and the Russian designer Olga Engel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wooden bench</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/wooden-bench/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/wooden-bench/</guid>
      <description>Wooden bench
The lightweight construction and compact size of the bench make it a convenient and practical piece of interior design. The intentionally primitive design is not an accent, but rather an addition to the interior. The uncomplicated light silhouette adds detail to the space while the wood adds materiality.
Size: 450x1000x450
Material: oak veneer
Photographer: Lizaveta Kulenenok
Available for order</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yard. A music venue</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/yard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/yard/</guid>
      <description>Yard. A music venue
Concept for the development of the former Experimental Plant of Technological Equipment in Minsk
The development of decayed industrial sites is a key factor in the renewal of Minsk. Tucked away amid residential quarters, such territories are often more viable than specially designed public spaces. Despite its enclosed nature and isolation from the streets, the Experimental Plant of Technological Equipment too has the potential to become a full-fledged and successful place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eternal peace</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/eternal-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/eternal-peace/</guid>
      <description>Eternal peace
Since childhood I have regularly visited cemeteries. Of all the reasons to be there, funeral is by far the least common. In Belarus people visit cemeteries on religious holidays, but also for important family celebrations. At the cemetery they clean the graves of their relatives together, they introduce the new family members to the old, they remember their departed loved ones, finally they can talk and share a humble meal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knomary. Office</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/knomary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/knomary/</guid>
      <description>Knomary office
The starting point for our design was the initially complex configuration of the space, the wide range of wall materials, variations in ceiling height and floor level. To create a comfortable environment, we decided to tie the existing surfaces together with a common light grey colour, against which the black pavilion with private offices and a call booth stands out. This way we were free to introduce a variety of complementary materials and shapes of furniture: stainless steel, light wood, red textile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melancholy space</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/melancholy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/melancholy/</guid>
      <description>Melancholy space
Melancholy is a form of mental illness manifested in a prolonged state of sadness. Characteristic for melancholy is a solemn and pensive mood, often the result of a more thoughtful view on life. In small doses it is a defence reaction of the psyche, a restorative slumber bringing rebirth.
Postmodernism created an environment brimming with signs and meanings. This obscures the distinction between essential and secondary. An apartment leaves you alone with yourself, lets you escape the belarusian reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Touchable distance” Exhibition design</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/touchable-distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/touchable-distance/</guid>
      <description>“Touchable distance” Exhibition design
The unequivocal times we’re currently facing have entailed an abrupt change in the ways we interact with each other, and our perception of the surrounding world. This shift in our form of communication has not only led to societal frustration, but also pushed us to rethink familiar concepts. Daily life and human behavior have significantly changed with a sense of increased fear and anxiety. Breaking away from our physical connections, in the most basic sense, we are forced to seek interaction online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minsk Light Industry Accessory Factory. Facade renovation</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/light-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/light-industry/</guid>
      <description>Minsk Light Industry Accessory Factory. Facade renovation
The building of a former accessories factory is located in the central part of Minsk and dates back to the 1950s. It is a typical example of functionalism in soviet architecture.
The new owner wants to transform the empty building into a business hub where IT-companies coexist with educational establishments and cultural institutions. We were asked to adapt the run-down facades for the new function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor and leisure club</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/labour-and-leisure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/projects/labour-and-leisure/</guid>
      <description>Labor and leisure club
Located in Minsk and built around the 1950s, the building represents a typical example of soviet architecture. To include it in the modern economical and cultural contexts while preserving its architectural identity was the leading motive of the project.
The building is a legacy of the soviet industrial architecture of the mid 20th century. The combination of red walls with white window frames and decor was one of the characteristic features of industrial buildings of that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steel frame armchair</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/steel-armchair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/steel-armchair/</guid>
      <description>Steel frame armchair
The armchair is developed for a private space. Rigorous design, inspired by furniture of the Modernist era, is conveyed by the simplicity of form and the choice of materials. The frame is made of stainless steel, the seat is upholstered with a rough dark fabric. The design by Radical Passive was realised in collaboration with two Belarusian manufactures.
Date: 2020
Photographer: Lizaveta Kulenenok</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useless tree</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/useless-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/useless-tree/</guid>
      <description>Useless tree
At one time Alexander Brodsky used to take photos of old garages, while John Pawson - of the sky. Both saw in it architectural value, albeit this value was personal. Perhaps if one wants to learn how to create simple and comprehensible design, first one has to learn to see beauty in the mundane, to understand the nature of these simple things: how the owners of those garages adapted the standard soviet structure to their needs or how atmospheric pollution in different regions changes the colour of sky.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
