<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Objects on Radical Passive</title>
    <link>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Objects on Radical Passive</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://radicalpassive.com/objects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Camille</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/camille/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/camille/</guid>
      <description>Camille
A big enveloping cloud. It&amp;rsquo;s bigger than a normal chair: its dimensions defy common standards. You don&amp;rsquo;t sit on this chair, you stay in it. Furthermore, sitting in the chair is just one of the possible poses. Its soft, rounded shape gives it a relaxed and stable character. The upholstery is made of white textured corduroy.
The chair is inspired by the works of the French studio Pierre Augustin Rose and the Russian designer Olga Engel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auguste</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/auguste/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/auguste/</guid>
      <description>Auguste
The chair is on the border between a functional object and a sculpture. It was specifically designed to stand out in the interior. It has no backrest, making it more of a cushioned stool. The armrests flow smoothly from the shape of the seat. The solid base gives the entire structure stability. The distinctive shape is accentuated by the black velour upholstery.
The chair is inspired by the works of the French studio Pierre Augustin Rose and the Russian designer Olga Engel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wooden bench</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/wooden-bench/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/wooden-bench/</guid>
      <description>Wooden bench
The lightweight construction and compact size of the bench make it a convenient and practical piece of interior design. The intentionally primitive design is not an accent, but rather an addition to the interior. The uncomplicated light silhouette adds detail to the space while the wood adds materiality.
Size: 450x1000x450
Material: oak veneer
Photographer: Lizaveta Kulenenok
Available for order</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steel frame armchair</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/steel-armchair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/objects/steel-armchair/</guid>
      <description>Steel frame armchair
The armchair is developed for a private space. Rigorous design, inspired by furniture of the Modernist era, is conveyed by the simplicity of form and the choice of materials. The frame is made of stainless steel, the seat is upholstered with a rough dark fabric. The design by Radical Passive was realised in collaboration with two Belarusian manufactures.
Date: 2020
Photographer: Lizaveta Kulenenok</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
