<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Журнал on Radical Passive</title>
    <link>https://radicalpassive.com/ru/journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Журнал on Radical Passive</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://radicalpassive.com/ru/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Башня и колоннада</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/ru/journal/tower-and-colonnade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/ru/journal/tower-and-colonnade/</guid>
      <description>Башня и колоннада
Конкурс от А-100 ART «Единство в разнообразии»
Концепция двух объёмно-пространственных композиций для конкурса в «Новой Боровой»
Идея Концепция Посыл
Ключевые слова: сообщество, объединение вокруг важного, взаимоподдержка, сила единства, дружба, соседство, архитектурная типология, типология «башня», типология «колоннада», разность, но схожесть.
Мы не выбираем времена, в которых нам жить. Но мы выбираем путь, который нам предстоит пройти.
15 ноября 2020 года в районе “НоваяБоровая” произошло повреждение системы водоснабжения. В домах на несколько дней полностью исчезли вода и отопление.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eternal peace</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/ru/journal/eternal-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/ru/journal/eternal-peace/</guid>
      <description>Eternal peace
Since childhood I have regularly visited cemeteries. Of all the reasons to be there, funeral is by far the least common. In Belarus people visit cemeteries on religious holidays, but also for important family celebrations. At the cemetery they clean the graves of their relatives together, they introduce the new family members to the old, they remember their departed loved ones, finally they can talk and share a humble meal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useless tree</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/ru/journal/useless-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/ru/journal/useless-tree/</guid>
      <description>Useless tree
At one time Alexander Brodsky used to take photos of old garages, while John Pawson - of the sky. Both saw in it architectural value, albeit this value was personal. Perhaps if one wants to learn how to create simple and comprehensible design, first one has to learn to see beauty in the mundane, to understand the nature of these simple things: how the owners of those garages adapted the standard soviet structure to their needs or how atmospheric pollution in different regions changes the colour of sky.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
