<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal on Radical Passive</title>
    <link>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal on Radical Passive</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://radicalpassive.com/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Minsk.alive (2020-2022)</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/minsk.alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/minsk.alive/</guid>
      <description>Minsk.alive (2020-2022)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Театр</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B0%D1%82%D1%80/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B0%D1%82%D1%80/</guid>
      <description>Театр
Этот проект не имеет отношения к реальному проектированию. Его итогом не стали привлекательные визуализации фасадов и альбомы чертежей с материалами и конструктивными узлами.
Это наш поиск подходящей архитектурной типологии театра, где зритель немного ближе к актерам, а актеры немного свободнее в выборе материала и его подачи. Наше небольшое размышление над тем, как здание может стать более открытым к диалогу и взаимодействию артиста и зрителя. Наш способ проявить солидарность с актерами Купаловского театра.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tower and colonnade</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/tower-and-colonnade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/tower-and-colonnade/</guid>
      <description>Tower and colonnade
Entry for A-100 sculpture competition “Unity in Diversity”
In November 2020, Minsk neighborhood New Bor suffered water and heating cuts attributed to vandalism. For several days people from all over the city were delivering bottles of water and portable radiators in a show of solidarity. The event brought together complete strangers in their desire to help fellow citizens. This phenomenal unity and self-organization must never be forgotten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eternal peace</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/eternal-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/eternal-peace/</guid>
      <description>Eternal peace
Since childhood I have regularly visited cemeteries. Of all the reasons to be there, funeral is by far the least common. In Belarus people visit cemeteries on religious holidays, but also for important family celebrations. At the cemetery they clean the graves of their relatives together, they introduce the new family members to the old, they remember their departed loved ones, finally they can talk and share a humble meal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useless tree</title>
      <link>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/useless-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radicalpassive.com/journal/useless-tree/</guid>
      <description>Useless tree
At one time Alexander Brodsky used to take photos of old garages, while John Pawson - of the sky. Both saw in it architectural value, albeit this value was personal. Perhaps if one wants to learn how to create simple and comprehensible design, first one has to learn to see beauty in the mundane, to understand the nature of these simple things: how the owners of those garages adapted the standard soviet structure to their needs or how atmospheric pollution in different regions changes the colour of sky.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
